(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T17:28:21.493030",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ほい！
Hoi!
ミュートじゃないわ！
I wasn't muted!
ポルカだよ～！
It's Polka~!
どうだったぞ？良くない？
How was that? Pretty good, right?
謎のリアリティ。
Mysterious realism.
ヤッホー！ポルカだよ！イェーイ！
Yahoo! It's Polka! Yay!
もう、昨日までの全ては伏線だったんだよ。
Everything up until yesterday was just foreshadowing.
これがポルカのサーカステント！
This is Polka's circus tent!
おまるさ…おまる！おまる！
Omaru sa... Omaru! Omaru!
おまる座、ポルカサーカスよろしくね！イェーイ！
Omaru Troupe, Polka Circus, please support us! Yay!
ホロライブ2期生、おまるポルカです！見てる？
Hololive 2nd Gen, Omaru Polka here! Watching?
あれ？あ、そういう感じなんだ。
Huh? Ah, so that's how it is.
ど、どこにそのカード配置されてるの？
Wh-where are those cards placed?
あ、ありがとうございます！どうも、あの、いつもね、見てくださってありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much! Thanks, um, thank you always for watching!
どうも、イェーイ！イェーイ！
Thanks, yay! Yay!
なんか、あれだね、テレビっぽいな。
Kind of, you know, looks like TV.
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat me well!
あの、早速なのですが、どうですかこの、この、何？体？
Um, right away, how do you like this, this, what? Body?
いつも、多分見えてないと思うんだけど、どうなんだろう。
You probably can't see it usually, but I wonder how it is.
あらあらあらあら、ちょっとね、カメラをね、そう。
Oh my, oh my, you know, the camera, yeah.
あの、あれ、あ、なんだっけ、動く、動く、なんかアップにするやつ、アップにするやつ。
Um, what was it, moving, moving, something that zooms in, something that zooms in.
アップにするやつカメラくださーい！
Camera that zooms in, please!
魔法のカメラ、うわっ！うわっ！ちかっ！はずかし！はずかし！はずかし！やば！
Magic camera, woah! Woah! So close! No way!
ヤッホー！見える？はい。
Yahoo! Can you see? Yes.
えい！えい！えい！あ、あの、じっくり見…あーそんなあーそうそうそうそう！
Ei! Ei! Ei! Ah, um, look closely... ah, yeah, right, right!
あーもうちゅっちゅっちゅってして、ちゅっちゅっちゅってして。
Ah, do chu-chu-chu, do chu-chu-chu.
やっぱ見える、やった！いい！
Still visible, yay! Great!
じゃあ、あの、ほらね、この辺りとか何が気になるかい？君たちは。
Well then, um, you see, what about this area are you curious about?
おおー！え？
Oooh! Eh?
ねえ、このおへそすごくない？おへそ。
Hey, isn't this belly button amazing? Belly button.
どう？お腹今日冷えてないよ？大丈夫だよ。おへ、近いな。
How is it? My stomach isn't cold today? It's fine. Bell--, close.
めっちゃ近くも、ちょ、あの、やっぱやめよう。
Too close, wait, um, actually let's stop.
やっぱ恥ずかしいからやめようか。え、ほら後ろとかどう？
It's embarrassing so let's stop. Eh, look at the back or how is it?
意外と見たことない。
Surprisingly you haven't seen it.
リボンもこうなってます。
The ribbon is like this too.
ないんだよね、ポルカの後ろ姿。
It's not there normally, Polka's back view.
つけね、こうなってるんだよ。
The base is like this.
これ切る時なんか、こ、じゃあってなって大変で。
When cutting this, like, bo- and it's tough.
はい。あ、ありがとう、可愛い。ありがとう。
Yes. Ah, thank you, cute. Thank you.
いや、初めて見たでしょ？そうでしょう？
Well, you saw it for the first time, right? Right?
なかなか
Quite...
なかなかそうね。え？何？
Quite so, yeah. Eh? What?
下から？え？下から？お、お、お、お！
From below? Eh? From below? Oh, oh, oh, oh!
それは、あ、ちょ、待って待って待って、やめてやめてやめて！
That is, ah, wait, wait, wait, stop stop stop!
バンバンバン！バンバンバンバン！やめてよ、バンバンバン！
Bang bang bang! Bang bang bang! Stop it, bang bang!
あ、ありがとう。おま…
Ah, thank you. Omaru...
なんか危ないところになるとこだった。
It was almost becoming a dangerous situation.
よかった、これで平気？
Phew, is this fine?
尻尾見る？
Want to see my tail?
あと、もうちょっと……
And a bit more...
あの、ここですか？
Um, right here?
見られへんて？
You can't see it?
えい えい えい えい！
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
尾丸ポルカの「おまる」って、おっぽが丸いからおまるなんだよ！
Omaru Polka's name comes from having a round tail!
あの、寝るとき丸まるんすわ。
Um, when I sleep, I curl up into a ball.
こう……寝る時、これ、丸まって
Like this... When I sleep, it curls up
きゅってなるから、おまる何なんだけれど
and gets all tight, so it's "Omaru"...
何？アホ毛？
What? Ahoge?
回らんよ！回らん！すまん！
It doesn't spin! It doesn't spin! Sorry!
ちょっと今回の技術は足りんかった、私の。私がね、これもっと混ぜれるようになったら空も飛べるかもしれない。
My technology wasn't enough this time. If I get better at mixing this, I might even be able to fly through the sky.
もしかしたら、ホルグラがやってくるかもしれない。
Maybe HoloGra might even come for me.
みんな、お問い合わせよ！
Everyone, contact management!
よし、これでいいだろ？え、これでよかった？
Alright, this is fine, right? Huh, was this good?
回って欲しか、ポルカが回るよじゃ、ほら！
You wanted me to spin? Polka will spin, look!
これでいいだろ！ほら！私、私が回るからほら！これで満足か！ほら！
Is this good! Look! I'm spinning, look! Are you satisfied with this! Look!
よし！いいぞ、いいぞ！回ってる？どう？回ってる？あんま？あんまか？
Alright! Great, great! Am I spinning? How is it? Am I spinning? Not much? Not really?
え？
Huh?
え、じゃあ、どうしよう？え、何？あ、なんか、あ、何これ？何これ？
Huh, well, what should I do? Huh, what? Oh, what, oh, what is this? What is this?
アーティストやん！
I look like an artist!
あ、なんかすごいアーティストっぽくなってる、いま。
Oh, I'm looking super artistic right now.
なにこれ？パリコレ？
What is this? Paris Collection?
すごくない？ほらこれ？出られる？
Isn't this amazing? Look at this! Can I make it in?
ミラクルなボディが、魅惑的なおまるポルカ。
A miraculous body, the alluring Omaru Polka.
魅惑のボディが本当に魅惑的です。
This miraculous body is truly alluring.
え？こんなんでいいよっちゃう。よっちゃう、よっちゃう！それよりあと愛想がなさすぎたろ！
Huh? Is this really okay? I'm getting dizzy, dizzy! More importantly, I was way too unfriendly!
おいおいおい見えるか！見えるか！
Hey hey hey, can you see? Can you see?
おい！あれ？あ、あの、ここです！ここです！
Hey! Huh? Oh, um, right here! Right here!
ここにいますよ！いーたーいーたーいーたー！ただいまー！
I'm right here! Ow ow ow ow! I'm back!
ステージでしょ！すごくない？
It's a stage! Isn't it amazing?
いいでしょ？あれ、おかえり。ヤッホー！どう？
Isn't it nice? Oh, welcome back. Yahoo! How is it?
ええ、ごめんどう、なんか見たいとこある？
Um, sorry, is there anything you'd like to see?
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ポルカのサーカスの雰囲気がすごい、あとで見せてあげるからちょっと待ってな。ウインクバチコーン！うわーい！ありがとー！
Polka's circus atmosphere is amazing. I'll show you later, so just wait. Wink batchi-kōn! Yay! Thank you!
鎖骨？なんかマニアックじゃない？それ。見えるじゃんこれ。見えるでしょ、別に！ええ？
Collarbone? Isn't that a bit maniac? You can see it. You can see it, right? Huh?
ええ？あの、もっと見せして。うし、うし、後ろ？え？なんか、え、え、え、え、え？
Huh? Um, show me more. Back, back, back? Huh? What, huh, what, what, what, what?
あ、普通にこれ、恥ずかしいな。なんか、ちょっと、いるよ！なんかいる！おっおっ、お！
Ah, this is actually pretty embarrassing. Wait, there are some! There are some! Oh oh oh!
え？なんかちょっと、いるよ！なんかいる！な、おっお！
Huh? Wait, there are some! There are some! Wh- oh oh!
え？お前たち？お前たち！まさか……
Huh? You guys? You guys! No way...
来てくれたんか、ポルカのために。ビデオだらにせんけど、お前ら。
You came for Polka's sake? Even though you're not streaming, you guys.
来てくれたんか。うちのオマルじゃいよ。マジこいつら……
You came for me. You're my Omaru. Seriously, these guys...
あの、生きてる？生きてるのかな、こいつら？え？ほら、ほら、ほら、ほら、ほら！
Um, are they alive? Are they even alive, these guys? Huh? Look, look, look, look, look!
それで、ポルカどこにいるでしょうか？
So, where do you think Polka is?
尾丸ポルカはどこにいるでしょうか？
Where is Omaru Polka?
あ、わかるわ、これ。
Ah, I know this.
話さんといって！
Don't talk!
尾丸ポルカどこにいるでしょうか？
Where is Omaru Polka?
おるな。わかるな、これ。
I'm here. I know this.
えー、すごい！座因くんかわいいね。
Eh, amazing! Zain-kun is cute.
これなんか……これ……これ……ちょっと足蹴にしちゃってる。足蹴に、ごめんごめん！踏んでない、踏んでない！違う違う違う、踏んでない踏んでない！埋まった。最多。
This thing... this... this... I'm kind of kicking them. Kicking them—sorry, sorry! I'm not stepping on them, I'm not! No no no, I'm not stepping on them! I'm buried. Most.
そっか。じゃあ、お前らよく来てくれた。
I see. Well, thanks for coming.
ま、一応これから始まるから。お前らよく見ておく。
Well, anyway, it's about to start. You guys watch closely.
じゃあ、ハイジャォ。落ちろ、落ちろ！
Well, let's go back. Fall, fall!
そんな帰り方あるか！びっくりした！
What kind of way to leave is that! That startled me!
なんかサプライズ出演かのサプライズ解散にまっちゃった。いい演出だったね。
It turned out to be like a surprise appearance or surprise disbandment. That was a good production.
まあ、というわけね、ちょうど、まあ、先日花ふぶきニアふぶきでもね、サーカステントが作り終えたということで、ええ、サーカステント
Well, anyway, right, um, just the other day, with Hana Fubuki Near Fubuki as well, we finished building the circus tent, so um, the circus tent
こちら、ようやくね、みんなもね、迎い入れられたということで、テントをお見せたいと思います。
Here, finally, everyone was able to be welcomed in, so I'd like to show you the tent.
さあ、まずね、これどういう感じになってるかっていうのをね、ちょっとね見てほしいんだけど。
Now, first, I want you to see how this looks.
おおー！これだよ！求めてたのは！
Whoa! This is it! This is what I was looking for!
あそこにブランコがあってね。あそこにね、あのね、登るのよ。
There's a trapeze over there. And you, you know, climb up there.
ぐるぐる動かすねんよ
Moving it around and around!
あーいいわ すごげえ！
Oh, nice! Amazing!
トランポリンもある！ トランポリンもある！
There's a trampoline! There's a trampoline!
トランポリンもある！
There's a trampoline!
あ、大砲もある！ そこに入るんだよ、誰か。
Hey, a cannon! Someone's gonna go in there.
今度入れよう、誰か。
Who's gonna go in next?
え、すごい！ いいですねー！
Whoa, that's awesome! This is great!
やったー！ ははは！
Yay! Ha ha ha!
これ、一つ夢叶っちゃったんだよなー。
This has literally made one of my dreams come true.
やべっ！ えへへ！
Yikes! Hehehe!
どうする？
What should I do?
え？どうしよう？
あ、やべ、見られた。 ははは！
Ah, oops, they saw me. Hahaha!
すげえ！ ねぇ、見て見て！やばい、やばい！
Awesome! Hey, look, look! Oh, no!
ステージちゃんとしてある。 ライトもある。
There's a proper stage, and lights too.
え、でもさ、なんか、なんだろ？
Wait, um... what is this?
これさ、どうも？
How is this?
なんかまだ、何かがまだ足りない気がする。
I feel like something's still missing.
いや、何かな？ 何が足りないんだろうな。
Yeah, what is it? What could be missing?
うーん、振り付け下手だなー。 ははは！
Hmm, my swing dancing is pretty clumsy, huh? Hehe!
ライオンの火の輪？ 違う、違う、違う！
Lion firework? No, no, no!
まあ、観客もそうなんだけど、今日はまだね、お披露目だから。
Well, the audience is too, of course, but today is my grand reveal, so...
えっと、なんてんだっけ？ プレ……オープン？ プレ……サービス？
Um, what do you call it? Play... open? Play... service?
というわけで！ さあ、行きます！このサーカスの変身を……第2形態？第2形態？ よーい！ ドーン！
So, let's go! Let's transform this circus into its second form! Second form? Yay! Down!
welcome！あなたは選ばれし
Welcome! You are the chosen ones,
ポルカサーカスの初めてのお客様！
Omaru Circus's very first guests!
やあやあ お待たせしました
Thank you so much for waiting.
とてもハッピーな動物たち
Such happy animals,
ユカイでかわいい 魔界の子からエルフまで
from quirky and cute magical beings to elephants!
TV SHOWじゃない ここだけのサーカス
It's not a TV show, it's a circus like no other!
It's show time！！
It's Show Time!!
なにがみたい？ どんなことでもしてあげる
What do you want to see? I'll do anything for you!
私は座長 その名も尾丸ポルカ
I'm the ringmaster, Omaru Polka!
ぜったい笑顔にさせちゃうぜ スマイル！ それでは最後まで付き合ってもらうからな！
I'll definitely make you smile! So stick with me till the very end!
are you ready？
Are you ready?
さあさあ近くにおいで きっと誰もが仰天
Come closer, everyone will look up in awe!
奇想天外なショーの始まりさ
The beginning of an out-of-this-world show!
グッと惹かれるでしょ？ おっと！押さないでね
Intrigued, aren't you? Hey, don't push!
それでは準備OKですか？
Then is your preparation OK?
愉快な動物たち 玉乗りピエロ
Quirky animals, ball-balancing clowns,
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうでしょ！
heart-pounding, thrilling shows!
真っ赤な輪くぐらせ 綱渡りして
Passing through fiery hoops, walking the tightrope!
ちょっとくらいのドジなんてご愛嬌よ
A few blunders are just part of the charm!
come on！light up！ とっておきのライブ
Come on! Light up! A special live performance!
ボッとしてないで もっともっと手を叩こう！
Don't just stare blankly, clap your hands more!
ほらほら落ち着いておいて
Hey, stay calm and keep up,
目も回るようなサーカス きっとここだけだよ
a dizzying circus, truly one of a kind!
ホログラムみたい キラキラ 奇跡が踊る
Like a hologram, sparkling miracles dance!
いつかは世界中を虜にしちゃうぞ
Someday, we'll take over the whole world!
うーん 明日の演目はどうしよっかな
Hmm, what should tomorrow's show be?
屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議さ
A secret strategy meeting behind the roof!
いっぱいの観客席がアッと驚くような とびきりのショーを見せましょう
We'll show you a breathtaking, amazing show!
思い付いたら ジッとしていられない
Once you think of it, you can't stay still,
座員を引き連れて let's go！
bringing the crew along, let's go!
ねぇ あれがやりたい！ これもやりたい！
Hey, I want to do that! I want to do this too!
どうして時間って足りないの？
Why is there never enough time?
みんなの声が聞きたい！
I want to hear everyone's voice!
よろしくお願いします いこっ！ わっ！わっ！わっ！わっ！ イッツ・ジャンプ！
Let's go! One, two, three, four! Jump!
ちゃんと手叩いた？
Did you clap properly?
ポルカ げえじぇ！
Polka, geez!
うまくいかなくって 空回りばかりで
Even when things don't go well and I'm just spinning my wheels,
少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど 見ててね
and there are days when I feel down, just watch me, okay?
大丈夫 いつまでも クヨクヨしてられないし
It's alright, you can always rely on me,
顔を上げて 今日のステージが ほら ね！待ってるのさ
so lift your head up, today's stage is, see, waiting for you!
ポルカおるか？ ポルカおるんか？
Is Polka here? Is Polka around?
ポルカおるか？ ポルカ歌うか♪
Is Polka here? Polka's gonna sing!♪
ポルカおるか？ ポルカ終わるか？
Is Polka here? Is Polka all done?
ポルカおるか？ ポルカ踊るか♪
Is Polka here? Polka's gonna dance!♪
笑いよ！ ポルカおるか？
Come on, laugh! Is Polka here?
ポルカおるか？
Is Polka around?
ポルカおるんか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカ歌うか♪
Will Polka sing?
ポルカおるんか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka finish?
終わらない！
Not happening!
ポルカ踊るか♪
Will Polka dance?
強く強く願うんだ
Wishing so strongly and deeply,
どんな夢だってきっとそうきっと叶うはず
No matter what dream it is, it's bound to come true.
何も怖くない
Nothing is scary.
みんなの声は全部ちゃんと届いてるよ
Everyone's voices have all reached me properly.
さぁ新しい次元 新しい舞台へ
Now, to a new dimension, to a new stage,
もっともっと突き進もう！
Let's push further and further ahead!
まだまだ付いておいで 笑い転げちゃうサーカス
Keep up with us! A circus that will make you roll with laughter,
絶対ここだけだよ 初めての仲間
This is the only place, our first friends!
景色に心も踊る 今にも世界中を
Our hearts dance with the scenery, about to captivate the whole world,
虜にしちゃうから目を離しちゃダメだぞ
So don't take your eyes off me!
普通に
I honestly
泣きそうになった。
almost cried.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ホログラムサーカスでした！
That was Hologram Circus!
ポルカのね、オリジナル曲になっております。
This is my original song, Polka's.
あ、この前もね、MVが公開されたんですが、後ろでね流してもらいながら
Ah, the MV was released the other day too, while having it play in the background—
かぶせてもらいながら、やっぱ躍動感あるとあれやな、もう外れてしまう
And overlaying it, you know, when there's so much liveliness, it just slips right off!
胸が、ほえ、ほえって。ん？
My chest goes "whoa, whoa." Hm?
外れ、外れではないな。外れではないな。よし。
Well, it didn't slip off. It didn't slip off. Okay.
まあ、まあね、自分を追い詰めてこそのパフォーマンス、そしてこれを歌い切ってからさらに
Well, you know, a performance comes from pushing oneself to the limit, and then after singing this all the way through,
パフォーマンスをするのが、おまるポルカ！そして、おまるポルカ、ジャグリングに挑戦しまーす！
delivering an even greater performance—that's Omaru Polka! And now, Omaru Polka will take on a juggling challenge!
はあ、いけるかなこれ。
Hah, I wonder if I can do this.
どうなんだろジャグリングって、あの、いろんな種類がございましてね、まあ箱とかね、ステッキとかいろいろあるんですけども。
What is juggling like? There are various types, you know, like boxes, sticks, and various others.
はい、ということでこちら
Yes, so here—
まずは、えー、
First, um,
ステッキ！
a stick!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
これね、見てみて。ちゃんと、ポルカの、あれ？
Look at this, look. Properly, Polka's—huh?
うわもうねこれちゃんとヘデックの柄になっとるよ。ここの持ち手の部分。
Wow, look, this is actually patterned like Hedek's handle. This grip part.
おお、ええやんけ！ええ仕事するやんけ！
Oh, that's pretty good! Doing a great job!
こ、こ、こ、こうか？どや？
Is, is, is this it? How's that?
見える？
Can you see?
あ、いいね！いい仕事してますね！
Ah, nice! You're doing a great job!
さあ、まずは2本。
Now, first two.
大丈夫、まずは2本。落ち着いて。
It's fine, first two. Calm down.
これはたぶん普通の人でもできるはず。
This is probably something even an ordinary person can do.
いくぞ！
Here we go!
ほっ！ほっ！
Hop! Hop!
そう、なんだよ。そういうこともあるんだよ。
Yeah, well, things like that happen.
余裕でしたね。
Well, that was a breeze.
あの、ちょっと、失敗したら勝てジャッジしてくれますね。
If you fail, it judges you automatically.
よし、いくぞ！
Alright, here we go!
ほい！ほい！
Hoy! Hoy!
あ、ちょっちょっちょっ、みんな見ないで！見ないで！見ないで！
Ah, wait wait wait, everyone don't look! Don't look! Don't look!
ほっ！
Ho!
いや、まだいける、まだいける。まだ3本目を隠し持っているからな、私は。
No, I can still do it, I can still do it. I'm still hiding the third one.
3本目を出せばもう完璧だよ。
If I bring out the third one, it'll be totally perfect.
ここでね、3本、2本！勝つで！勝つ！
Right here, three, two! I'm gonna win! Win!
いくぞ！
Here we go!
えいっ！
Take this!
な、違う違う違う違う！終わらないで！
W-Wait, no no no no! Don't end it!
終わらないで！なんでそういうことするの！？もう！
Don't end it! Why do you do things like that?! Seriously!
あ、分かった。ちょさ、ねえ、ステッキくんさ、あの、こうさ、やるからさ、ちょっとなんかこう言う感じ、こう言う感じ。
Ah, I get it. Hey, stick-kun, um, since we do it like this, make it feel a bit like... like this, like this.
じゃ、行きます！それでは行きます！はい！
Well, here we go! Alright, here we go! Yes!
おっ、ほら見て見て！ほら！ほら！ほらほらほらほら！ほら、ほら、ほらほらほらほらほら！どう？どう？どう？どう？どう？
Oh, look, look! Look! Look! Look look look look! Look, look, look look look look look! How is it? How is it? How is it? How is it?
もうちょっと、もうちょっと大ぶり、大ぶりで行こう！
A little more, a little more big, let's go big!
おっ、おっ、完璧完璧完璧！えっ？
Oh, oh, perfect, perfect, perfect! Eh?
お披露目でもすべるん？
Even at my debut showcase?
ありがとうね、ステキ君本当に。
Thank you so much, Steki-kun.
ステキ君がいい仕事してくる
Steki-kun is doing such a good job.
嘘でしょ
No way.
ああ、わかった。
Ah, I get it.
ちょっともうちょっとね。
Just a little bit more.
多分ね、いけるわこれ。わかった、いきます。
Maybe I can do this. I got it, here I go!
もう1回ならいける、いける気がする。
One more time, I think I can do it.
最後、ラストチャレンジ！
Final, last challenge!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
いくぞ、いくぞ！
Here we go, here we go!
おらっと！おらっと！
Take this! Take this!
おっしゃい！
Alright!
あ、いい、うまい、うまい、うまい、うまい、うまい、うまい！
Ah, nice, I'm good, I'm good, I'm good!
え、超上手じゃん、すごいすごい！
Eh, I'm super good! Amazing, amazing!
え、うまい、うまい、うまい、なにごり、なにごり、なにごり、うまい、うまい、うまい…おわあ！
Eh, good, good, good, what is this... woah!
はあ！
Ha!
なんでも笑いに変える…
Turning everything into a joke...
あれ、だめでしたかね？どうでした？
Was that no good? How was it?
え、あーー！
Eh, aaah!
違います、終わりません！
No, it's not over!
大丈夫です、あの、曲が欲しかったとかそういうわけじゃ…あ、カットイン。
It's fine, it's not like I wanted a song... Ah, cut in.
尾丸ポルカ、3Dをお披露目！
Omaru Polka's 3D Debut!
はい、というわけで、ここまでね、楽しかったという方は、#尾丸ポルカ3Dでつぶやいてください！
Right then, for those who enjoyed it up to here, please tweet with #OmaruPolka3D!
いや、どうでしたかジャグリング？
So, how was the juggling?
どうですか？
How is it?
じゃ、あ、すご、トレンドにも乗ってくれてるということで、本当にね、トレンディな尾丸ポルカをよろしくお願いします！
And, it's even trending, so thank you so much, please look favorably upon trendy Omaru Polka!
さあ、ジャグリング…できたよね？
Now, juggling... I did it, right?
今の、あれ、だめ？
That just now, was that no good?
怪しい、どっちかな？ちょ、だめ判定かな、これ。うーーん。
Suspicious, which is it? Is that a failure judgment? Hmm...
じゃ、わかった。わかった、ちょ、提案がひとつある。うちのサーカスで、まだあるんだ、道具が。
Well, I get it. I get it, wait, I have one proposal. In our circus, there are still more props.
そう、それは…
That is...
玉乗り。
Ball riding.
やはりね、玉に乗って、コロコロ、コロコロと進むのがやっぱ分かりやすいでしょ、みんなにも。
After all, riding on a ball and rolling along is easy for everyone to understand.
一番わかりやすいじゃん！一番わかりやすいでしょ？
It's the easiest to understand! Isn't it the easiest?
ということで、今日はこのね、玉をね、持ってくるわじゃ。ちょ、持ってくる。
So today, I'll go bring this ball over. Wait, I'll bring it.
持って、持ってきたらいいのかな、これ。勝手に持ってきていいのかな。囲んじゃっていいやつかな。
Should I bring it here? Is it okay to just bring it? Can I enclose it?
ちょっと…玉くん、なんてつけよう。
Wait... Ball-kun, what should I name you?
玉くん。
Ball-kun.
あ、行ってくれた、行ってくれた（笑）
Ah, it went, it went.
このね、この…今運んでおります、うぇ！
This, this... I'm carrying it right now, ugh!
いや、ちょっとちっちゃいように見えるかもしれないけど、これ、えんきん…え、えんきん、どうして…めっちゃ大きいから！
Well, it might look a bit small, but this, perspective... Eh, perspective, why... It's super huge!
あ、ナイス！これめっちゃ大きいから。
Ah, nice! Because this is super huge.
これにね、乗ってコロコロと転がれば、ちょっと…サーカスかなって。どうかな。
If I ride on this and roll around, it's like... a circus. I wonder.
まあ、判定は…
Well, the judgment is...
あ、だめだよ、そんなカメラの（笑）
Ah, no good looking at the camera like that...
判定は任せた。乗ったぞ、私は玉に。
I'll leave the judgment to you. I've gotten on the ball.
行くぞ！
Here I go!
おっしゃ！
Alright!
行くぞ！
Here I go!
おっしゃあ！
Alright!
ほら、おれ、おれ、いしょ、いしょ、あれ、だめだ。
Look, ore, ore, heave-ho, heave-ho, wait, no good.
なんで？あー、い、いやー、どどどどど、じょじょじょじょじょ、こうやって行くんだよ、こうやって。わかるか？
Why? Ah, y-yeeeah, d-d-d-d-d, j-j-j-j-j, this is how you go, like this. Understand?
ほら、一番…一番分かりやすいちびっ子向け…え？なんで？
Look, the most... easiest to understand for kids... Eh? Why?
その悲しいカメラの視点やめて！
Stop that sad camera angle!
これ一番わかりやすいでしょ？ほらほら、こうやってほら、こうやって行くんだよって。
This is the easiest to understand, right? Look, look, this is how you go.
こうやって、こうやって…はあ、はあ。
Like this, like this... Ha, ha.
なんでこんな疲れてるんだ？うわあ！
Why am I so tired? Uwaah!
いける、まだいける。お前と、私の絆ならいけるぞ！
I can do it, I still can. If it's the bond between you and me, I can do it!
よいしょ。あの、じゃあちょっとゆっくりここでね、はあ、はあ。よし。
Heave-ho. Well then, slowly right here, ha, ha. Alright.
え？なんで怪しいって言ってるの？うそ。
Eh? Why are you saying it's suspicious? No way.
ちなみにこの初めて見る人にわかんないと思うけど、このね、「さす」っていうのはね、「怪しいな」って、「怪しいな」って言ってるみんな、「怪しいな」って言ってるの。
By the way, people seeing this for the first time might not get it, but this 'sasu' means everyone saying 'that's suspicious'.
怪しくなるだろ、これ全然。
It gets suspicious, doesn't it? Not at all.
ほら！ほらあ！
Look! Looook!
え、うまい！やばい！めっちゃうまくなくない？
Eh, good! No way! Aren't I super good?
どうですか？これ判定もお願いします！
How is it? Please judge this too!
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、今帰ってきたんだよ。どうかな？
Wait, wait, wait, I just came back now. How is it?
うまくない？ほらほらほらほらほらほらほらほら！ほらほらほらほら！
Aren't I good? Look look look look look look look look!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、あ、あ…（笑）
Ah, ah, ah...
あ、うまいな、これ。あ、これ、これ片足でもいけ、いけ、いけ、いけ、いけ…
Ah, I'm good at this. Ah, this, this, even on one leg I can go...
おおおー！
Oooh!
どういう？どういう？
What's this? What's this?
え、だめ全然？だめ？だめかなあ？うまいんでしょ、ちょ、これ。
Eh, totally no good? No good? Is it no good? I'm good at it, right?
よし、なかなか、これはさすがに…
Alright, fairly... this is definitely...
カッコいいでしょ？
Cool, right?
どうだ？
How's that?
どう... どうだ？
How... how's that?
え？
Huh?
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
あ、じゃあわかった。玉の上でジャグリングするわ。
Ah, then I get it. I'll juggle on top of the ball.
え？ 痛っ！
Eh? Ouch!
あーー！ たまくーーん！
Ahhh! Tama-kun!
たまくん、楽しいことになっちゃった。
Tama-kun, this turned into something fun.
大丈夫かな？
Are you okay?
元気？
You good?
いっこいっこ。
One by one.
大丈夫だよ、怪我してない？
Are you okay? Did you get hurt?
平気？ 大丈夫、一緒にいこうね。
Doing fine? It's okay, let's go together.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
よしよし。
There, there.
はいはいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
よし。これでいいやろ。
Alright. This should be fine.
よっしゃー。
Alright!
あ、ねえ、乗り方が難しいんだけど。
Ah, hey, riding this is hard.
あの、く、くっ、あ... 負けない！
Um, g-ggh, ah... I won't lose!
負けない！ 負けないぞ！
I won't lose! I won't lose!
ふっ、くっ、はーー！
Hn, gh, hahh!
よっしゃ！ 立てたー！
Alright! I stood up!
えーっと、やるか。
Umm, let's do it.
あの、あの、あの、あの、あの、あの、あの...
Um, um, um, um, um, um, um...
やります！ やります！
I'll do it! I'll do it!
もうカメラ引いちゃって！ できるから今！
Just pull back the camera! I can do it now!
ほら！ ほら！
Look! Look!
ほら！ ほら！ ほら！ よし！
Look! Look! Look! Alright!
あ、ちょっ... よ、うまい！ うまいまいまい！
Ah, wait... Go-, good! Good, good, good!
いいよいいよ。
That's good, that's good.
なんか、あれ？ 私マジックの人？ マジックの人なのかな？
Wait, huh? Am I a magician? Am I supposed to be a magician?
あ、こ、こ、こっちもっとこ、こ、そうそうそうそう、うまいね！
Ah, h-h-here more, h-h-, right, right, right, you're good!
あ、うまいうまい！ え、ステッキくんもだんだん動きがわっ、なんかこうさ、こうこい、あ、そうそうそうそうそう！
Ah, good, good! Eh, Stick-kun's movements are also starting to make sense, like this, like thi-, ah, right, right, right!
あ、いい... なんで！
Ah, goo— Why?!
いやあ、ざんげんき。
Man, what a relief.
見たな、今の。今の見てた？
You saw that just now. Were you watching just now?
どうだった？
How was it?
感想聞かせてよ。
Let me hear your thoughts.
あとで反省会？ やねうら大集会？
A debriefing session later? The attic mass meeting?
わかった。逆にしりょみ... あ、
I get it. To the surprise of the audien— ah,
ざいに... まさか悟されるとは。
to the audi- To think I'd be figured out.
逆に、逆にしりょみを向けれんなって...
Conversely, to direct suspicion toward the audience...
生まれると思わらんのだ。
I never thought it'd turn out like this.
あ、ただいま。
Ah, I'm back.
どうだった？
How was it?
え、あとでやねうら集合？ 呼び出し？
Eh, attic meeting later? A summons?
きっつ！ マジかよ。
So harsh! Seriously?
あ、やねうらで待ってて戻ってね、ありがとう。かわいいなお前ら本当に。
Ah, waiting for me in the attic and coming back, thank you. You guys are really cute.
えーっと、ちょっと息もね、こちらの問題なんですが、息を吸いながらとあれなんで皆さんどうかご着席ください。
Umm, catching my breath is also an issue here, but while catching my breath, everyone please take your seats.
立ってねえか。そっか。
You're not standing, are you. Right.
じゃあ、ちょポルカね、今日に向けて準備してしてきたものがあるから...
Well, Polka has something she prepared for today, so...
それを披露します。
I'll unveil it.
手紙を読まさせていただきたいと思います。
I would like to read a letter.
ちょっと、久しぶりの朗読ね。
It's been a while since I've done a reading.
少しちょっと、トチるかもしれないけど...
I might stumble a bit, but...
緊張します。
I'm nervous.
少女はおさない頃から人の目を気にする子でした。
Since she was a little girl, she was someone who cared about what others thought.
お母さんのそばをはなれない子でした。
She was a child who couldn't leave her mother's side.
いつも学校に行きたいと泣いていました。
She would always cry, saying she didn't want to go to school.
ある日、パフォーマンスに心をうばわれました。
One day, her heart was captured by a performance.
人の目にしてしまう彼女でしたが、舞台に立っているときだけは全てを忘れて全力を出す事に夢中になれました。
She was a girl who worried about people's eyes, but only when standing on stage could she forget everything and get lost in giving it her all.
とても幸せな場所を見つけたのです。
She had found a very happy place.
ホロライブにありがとうを伝えさせてください。
Let me express my gratitude to Hololive.
あたたかく迎え入れてくれた先輩。
The seniors who welcomed me warmly.
不安な時にたくさん相談に乗ってくれてうれしかったです。
I was happy when you listened to my many consultations during anxious times.
これからも、にぎやかな後輩だと思いますが、
Even if they might still be a noisy junior,
どうかだんだん受け入れてくれるとうれしいです。
I hope you'll gradually come to accept them.
まだ、多分変なやつだろうな！と思っていると思います。
I'm sure you think I'm still a weirdo!
まあ、まだ多分本当に、にぎやか、うるさいだけの変なやつだろうなと思って、この前もすごい難しい突っつみしちゃったし、そうだと、思っていると思います。
Well, you probably think I'm just a loud, noisy weirdo, and the other day I made things super awkward with my teasing, so I'm sure that's what you think.
それを変えていけるように、いっばいお話ししたいです。
I want to talk a lot so I can change that little by little.
どんな時も、そばにいてくれた五期生。
Gen 5, who stayed by my side no matter what.
ここでは言えないくらいに、泣いたり笑ったり、ぶつかりあったり、短い間なのにたくさんの思い出をありがとうございます。
In ways I can't even say here, crying, laughing, and clashing—thank you for so many memories despite such a short time.
本当になんか終わっちゃみたいに
It's not ending just yet,
終わんないよこれからだよそうここからまた一緒に歩いていきたいし
it's just beginning! I want us to keep walking together from here on out.
みんなも色々な場所で忙しくなっているのを見ると、どこかさみしいようなうれしいようなです。応援してくれているあなたへ。
When I see everyone getting busy in various places, it makes me feel a bit lonely yet happy... To you, who support me.
応援してくれているあなたへ。本当にありがとう。それしかないです。これ以上ないです。
Thank you so much. That's all there is. There is nothing more.
これからもよろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your continued support.
危なっかしいし、うるさい、急に静かになる感情のジェットコースター、今の乗りとか大丈夫だったかなってすぐ聞くような感じ、それもね書いちゃった手紙に。そう、そこのお前だよ、聞けよ。
A rollercoaster of emotions: clumsy, loud, suddenly quiet; always asking right away if I was okay—ah, I even wrote that in the letter! Yes, you right there, listen up.
いっぱい寄りかかります、だから受け止めいてください。その分、後悔はさせないです。
I'll lean on you a lot, so please catch me. But in return, I won't let you regret it.
そして見えないところで動いてくださっている人、これから交流する人、またよろしくお願いします。
And to those working behind the scenes, and those I'll interact with from now on, thank you for your continued support.
なんだかこれで終わりみたいな空気になってしまった…。
It felt a bit like we were wrapping up...
気を取り直して、まだまだ彼女のサーカスは始まったばかり。止まらず、想像をこえて、花を咲かせて、海の向こうまで届けていきます。
Let's pull ourselves together. Her circus has only just begun. Without stopping, exceeding imaginations, making flowers bloom, and delivering them across the sea.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your continued support.
というわけで、お手のコーナーでした！
And that wraps up the letter corner!
なんかこいついつも手紙読んでんなって感じしない？
Don't you feel like this guy is always reading letters lately?
最近ね手紙読みがちだな、これか。もうすぐこいつやばいことしてやめるのかって感じのテンションの時、僕めちゃんこ、ポルカは言いたいことを言ったんだよな。
Lately I've been reading a lot of letters. Whenever the tension feels like 'Is she gonna do something crazy and quit?', Polka said what she wanted to say.
どう、どどどどでした？あ、ありがとうありがとう。これからもこちらこそよろしくお願いします。
How was it? Ah, thank you, thank you. Thank you for your continued support as well.
まあ！気を取り直して！さっきのね、いやさっきの結果じゃまだ、まだ、まだ、まだ納得しない人がいるかもしれないからね。
Well! Let's pull ourselves together! The previous result... there might still be people who aren't convinced.
もう一個えもかん残しております！綱渡りのチャンス！いただけないでしょうか。こちら行こう、こう！挑戦させていただきます！ええ、拍手とコメントありがとうございます！がんばります！行ってきます！というわけで、綱渡りに挑戦！
I've got one more emotional trump card left! A chance at tightrope walking! May I have it? Let's go with this, like this! I accept the challenge! Thank you for the applause and comments! I'll do my best! Here I go! So, let's challenge the tightrope walking!
なんて、なかなか……
Well, you know...
初めての人が綱渡りしようとすると、
when someone tries tightrope walking for the first time,
なんだろうね、うーん。
I wonder what it's like... yeah.
やっぱ大変なことだし、ここの上から病院行っちゃったら
It's really tough, and if you fall from up here and end up in the hospital,
もう大変なことになっちゃうから。
it'll be a total disaster.
これを見て始めたいって思ったらやればいい。よし。
If you see this and want to try it, just go for it. Alright.
これ実実は、これも遠近法で30mぐらいあるから。
Actually, this is about 30 meters away due to perspective, so...
これ大丈夫だから。よし。
This is fine. Alright.
ちょっと待って、これ、ちゃんとほら！
Wait a second, look properly!
ほら！ねえ、ちゃんと！
Look! Hey, properly!
こうなるからさ、なに、落ちたら……
It turns out like this, if you fall...
落ちたら大変なんだよ、ワニの群れだよ！
If you fall it's a disaster, there's a swarm of crocodiles!
危ねえな。
That was close.
落ちたらワニの胸なんだからな。
If you fall, you're crocodile chow!
よし、いける。
Alright, I can do this.
これ、ちゃんと、うわああ！
This, properly... Whoa!
あの、パフォーマンスやるもの、ちゃんと前を向いて、
Um, when performing, you need to face forward,
いつも前を向いて……
and always face forward...
あ、ちょっとざい、ごめんね、ごめん、クッションになってくれてありがとう。最悪クッションになってくれ。
Ah, Zai—sorry, sorry, thanks for being a cushion. At worst, be my cushion.
あ、ちょっと待って、ざいーん！ざいーん！ごめん！
Ah, hold on! Zain! Zain! Sorry!
誰か行った？大丈夫？死んだ？
Did anyone go? Are you okay? Did you die?
大丈夫？大丈夫だった？ちょ、あの……
Are you okay? Were you okay? W-Um...
ざ、ざいんクッション助かった！危なかった！
Za—Zain cushion saved me! That was close!
みんながいなかったらマジ通り大変なことになるとこだったぜ！
If you guys weren't here, it would've literally been a huge disaster!
こんどこそ、まあ、今までにおわかりいただけたろう、どれぐらい大変なことだということか。
This time for sure... well, by now you probably understand just how tough this is.
よ、あ、めっちゃ下見てないす、いま。
Y—Ah, I'm totally not looking down right now.
全然してない、ざいん見てる、ざいん見てんだこっち、ざいん見てんだ！ざいん見てからよ！
I'm totally not, I'm looking at Zain, I'm looking at Zain over here, I'm looking at Zain! Look at Zain first!
踏んでないこれ、逆に？あれ？
Am I even stepping on it? Huh?
え？あ、あれ？ざいんの上歩いてない？ざいんの？あれ？これ、あれ？
Huh? Wh—What? Am I walking on Zain? On Zain? Huh? Is this... huh?
踏んでる？今もしもしかして。あ、踏んでるわ。ごめん。結構頭硬いんだな。
Am I stepping on it? Right now, could it be? Ah, I am stepping on it. Sorry. Your heads are pretty hard.
そして綱渡りも……やったー！イエーイ！
And the tightrope walking... We did it! Yay!
大成功！あれ？大成功だよね？今度こそ大成功！
Major success! Huh? It's a major success, right? This time for sure, major success!
あれ？なんか、空気が、あれ？え？ちょっと、どう収拾つけるんですか？だめですよ、そんな空気にしちゃったら。
Huh? Somehow, the atmosphere... Huh? Hey, how are you gonna wrap this up? You can't just make the atmosphere like that!
はい、大成功！大、あれ？ど、よーし、ねえ……
Yes, major success! Ma—Huh? Wh—Al—right, hey...
なんでそういうことりするの！大成功のムード出してよ！おねがいします！
Why would you do that?! Bring out the major success mood! Please!
おねがいします、あ、これね、行く方来る方では見せられなかったの溶けちゃうから。おねがいします、大成功にしてください！
Please, ah, this one—I couldn't show you the going and coming way because they'd melt. Please, make it a major success!
みんなのコメントで大成功にして！拍手のコメントで！ありがとうみんな！
Make it a major success with everyone's comments! With applause comments! Thank you everyone!
綱渡り、大成功！イエーイ！
Tightrope walking, major success! Yay!
え？成功したん？え？うそやん！うそやん！
Eh? I succeeded? Eh? No way! No way!
まあ、い、いいのかこれで。本当にいいの？ありがとう。うん、なんかね、いま
Well, i—is this okay? Is this really okay? Thank you. Yeah, well, right now...
なんていうんだろ、このサーカスのさ、照明音響スタッフとのいまやり取り戦いになってっからこっち。
How should I put it, my interaction and battle right now is with the circus lighting and sound staff over here.
ちょ、ゆっくりコメント読んで？
C-Could you read the comments slowly?
あ、ありがとう拍手！いやあ、ありがとう！いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！
Ah, thank you for the applause! Man, thank you! Yay, yay, yay, yay!
ちょ、さあ、ざいん、ざいん、ざいん、ざいん見てみたいんだよな、もうちょっと。
Hold on, man, Za—Zain, Zain, Zain, I wanna look at Zain a bit more.
ちょっと、見て、ポルカのことだけ見て今カメラ。ポルカのことだけ見て。見て、見て見て！
Hold on, look, just look at Polka right now, camera. Just look at Polka. Look, look, look!
ざいん、ざいん映したいんや！あれ？あれ？綱渡りショーストマジック！はっ！
Zain, I wanna show Zain! Huh? Huh? Tightrope walking show's magic! Ha!
きえへんな。見てる？ありがとう！
It won't disappear. Are you watching? Thank you!
でまね、綱渡りよね、消そうとしてるんだよね。どうも消えてくんねえな。
But you know, the tightrope walking, I'm trying to make it disappear. Somehow it won't disappear.
ポルカがこっち行くか。あともいいんじゃなこれ。
Should Polka go over here? That's fine too, right?
ていうことは照明にざいんが！
That means Zain is in the lighting!
え？いるか？い、いるのかこれ？今どこにいる？あ、いたいたいたいたいたいた！痛い痛い痛い痛い痛い！痛い痛い痛い痛い！やったー！綱渡
Eh? Are they there? A—Are they there? Where are they now? Ah, there they are, there they are! Ouch ouch ouch ouch! Ouch ouch ouch! Yay! Tightrope...
さり気なくすましてるんだけどさ
Acting all casual and composed...
ざいん君いた
Zain-kun was here.
いいな いいな みたいなの 今
Like, 'Must be nice, must be nice,' right now.
え、ほんとにいる？これ
Wait, is he really here?
おお、いるね
Oh, he's here.
いるね
He's here.
あ、いるじゃん
Oh, he is.
あ、なかなかいるね
Oh, there's quite a few.
埋まってんね
They're buried.
あ、爪も貫通したね
Oh, even the nails pierced through.
あ、これいいんじゃない？
Oh, isn't this good?
お、いいね、いいね
Oh, nice, nice.
行けた
I made it.
埋れてたね、今
I was buried just now.
イェーイ
Yay!
見える？
Can you see?
これすごい白い光だから
Because this is such a bright white light,
あれ？あ？
Huh? Ah?
さようなら
Goodbye.
笑わないで
Don't laugh.
笑わないでまだ
Don't laugh yet.
言いたいこといっぱいあるよ
I have so much I want to say!
I have so much I want to say...
あのー
Umm...
おまるポルカおるよ！
Omaru Polka is here!
ほら！
Look!
ポルカ！
Polka!
おるよ！
Is here!
おるおる！
Here she is!
おう！
Oh!
そういうのさ、え？
Things like that, huh?
なんか
Like...
あれやね、顔とかって見せだっけ？どんないい顔できるか
Right, did I show my face? Like, what kind of face I can make.
つーか、今からでもいいからさ、え？もうだいぶ笑った顔とか見せたと思うんだけどさ
I mean, even starting now is fine, like... I think I've already shown plenty of laughing faces, but,
何が出てくるか、はい！
What's going to come out? Ta-da!
でででででででででででででで、はい！
Ta-da-da-da-da-da-da-da! There!
遅れてきた、遅れてきた、え？え？
It's late, it's late, huh? Huh?
はい！
There!
今かよ！なんで顔に地蔵があるんだよ！
Now?! Why is there a Jizo statue on my face?!
もう一回行ってください、ドルムロール
Please do it again, drumroll please.
うーーっ！
Ugh!
ポルカは悪くないよね？ポルカは悪くないよね？
Polka didn't do anything wrong, right? Polka didn't do anything wrong, right?!
いくぞ、もう一回！
Let's go, one more time!
何が来るかな？何が来るかな？パン！
What's going to come? What's going to come? Bam!
はーい！可愛いおまるポルカです！よろしくね、いぇーい！
Hi! It's cute Omaru Polka! Nice to meet you, yay!
繋渡り、ハード？え？
Tightrope walking, hard mode? Huh?
なんか今、え？
Wait, right now, huh?
繋渡りにハードモードってあるんですか？
Is there a hard mode for tightrope walking?
まあわかんない、なんか、なんか、え？
Well, I don't know, like, like, huh?
ザイン君！
Zain-kun!
ちょ、ザイン君どういうこと？聞いてないよ！
Wait, Zain-kun, what do you mean? I didn't hear about this!
誰用意したの？ザイン、言ってみろ！
Who prepared this? Zain, say something!
ちょ、待って待って待って待って待って待って待って！はー？！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! What?!
え？！
Eh?!
うわ！
Woah!
おい、おいおいおいおいおいおい、いや
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, no...
ハード！
Hard!
で、そういう？あーあー、え？誰用意したの？え？
So, like that? Ah-ah, huh? Who prepared this? Huh?
今ならねばまだ間に合うよ
If it's now, we still have time.
どうする？どうする？
What should I do? What should I do?
今、今なら、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ！延命法って言ったけどほんとこれ延命法じゃないから！
Right now, right now... hey, hey, hey! I said it was a life-prolonging method, but this really isn't one!
た！
Ta!
ここからさ、どれぐらい高いかさ、カメラでで見えねえのかな
From here, I wonder if the camera can show how high it is.
足元に見えねえの
Can't you see my feet?
高くね？
Isn't it high?
え？
Huh?
処刑台じゃん！
This is a scaffold!
明日からいなくなるよ！公式ホームページクリックしたらもっと見るのコーナーにオマルポルカが居ることは私は今まで研究しなかったのに！
Starting tomorrow, I'll be gone! Even though I've never researched that Omaru Polka appears in the 'See More' corner when you click the official homepage!
ポルカ以外居るのにJPのここ、おかしいよ！ほんとに逆立ちよ、これいいの？
Except for Polka, JP is here, this is weird! Doing a handstand really, is this okay?
みんな、みんなおまるポルカを応援するポル！よし、私ならいける！やれる！
Everyone, cheer for Omaru Polka! Alright, I can do this! I can do it!
うっ！
Ugh!
いや、え、もうやばくない？これ、なんか
No, wait, isn't this already bad? This, like...
え、ちょっと待って、もう、もう、わー！終わっ
Wait, wait, wait, waah! It's ove—
せっ、おせっ、せっ、おせっ
Push, push, push, push!
せっ、おせっ、おせっ、おせっ、おせなーい！
Push, push, push, push, won't push!
いらっしゃい！いぇーい！
Welcome! Yay!
大成功ー！
Huge success!
せーの
Ready, set...
の、大成功！
No, big success!
せーの！大成功！
Ready, go! Big success!
こわい、まじまじまじまじ！
Scary, seriously, seriously, seriously!
それそれそれそれ、それ待てた。
That's it, I waited for that.
いや、しかしこれ
Man, but this...
高いな。
...is high.
これ、高くね？
Isn't this high?
え？今まで見たことなかったの？え？
Huh? You've never seen it until now? Huh?
え？ちょ、あの、え、え？
Huh? Hold on, um, huh, huh?
いやだってみ、下に高いのが、え？
I mean, look, there's a high one down below, huh?
夢？
A dream?
え、みんな見て？え？
Huh, everyone look? Huh?
え？え？え？いま、夢？え？
Huh? Huh? Huh? Right now, a dream? Huh?
夢を見たの？
Did I have a dream?
今までだって
Up until now, I mean
すごい綱渡りが
That amazing tightrope walk...
あれ？どういうこと？
Huh? What does that mean?
だって今、大成功ポルカ
I mean right now, successful Polka
このままじゃ死んじゃうよ？明日から配信なくなっちゃうよ？
If I stay like this, I'll die? My streams will stop tomorrow?
マリオカート大会も出れないじゃいいの？ってなってたのに。
Can I not even enter the Mario Kart tournament?
ん？
Hmm?
まあ何わともあれ大成功でした、えーい！
Well anyway, it was a big success, yay!
えー、やっほー！
Yay, yahoo!
まあこんなポルカサーカスだけどこれからもよろしくお願いします！
Well, this is Polka Circus, but please keep supporting us!
え、楽しかった？
Um, did you enjoy it?
色々ね、用意したんだ。
I prepared various things.
ザインくんも頑張ってたし。
Zaon-kun worked hard too.
ポルカも頑張んないと。
Polka has to work hard too.
え、なんでそんな詫びられるの？
Huh, why are you apologizing like that?
めっちゃ頑張ってろずえどや！どや！
I worked super hard, doyanya! Doya!
どうやー！
Doya!
よかった、楽しかったならありがとう。
Great, if you enjoyed it, thank you.
さてと。
Now then.
ん？
Hmm?
なんだい？
What is it?
お、このスポットライトさ、ちゃんとポルカに合わせて動いてる！今気づいた。
Oh, this spotlight is moving along with Polka! Just noticed.
ピンスポありがとう。ありがとうございます。
Thanks for the pinspot. Thank you very much.
すげえな。
That's amazing.
えっということはさ、これ、これ、動いてくれてたの？
Wait, does that mean this, this was moving for me?
はーい！
Hii!
え？お、生まれてきた。かわいい。
Huh? Oh, they were born. Cute.
かわいい、これさ、なんか
Cute, this, like,
え、なんか、君どこから来たの？
Um, like, where did you come from?
君どこから来たの？
Where did you come from?
どこに...うわっ！生まれた！
Where— Woah! Born!
君はどこから来たの？
Where did you come from?
いい子だね。
Such a good boy.
あ、あ、そんな引かないで引かないでどうしたの？
Ah, ah, don't pull back like that, what's wrong?
なんでそんな、何もしない、かわいいこと何もしないからどうしたの？
Why, I'm not doing anything cute, I'm not doing anything, what's wrong?
いい子だね、せっかくね、一緒にね、ここまで来たんだからね。これからも一緒にやってこうね。
There, there, since we've come this far together, let's keep doing our best together.
ね？
Right?
ザインくんは喋らないんです。
Zaon-kun doesn't speak.
え？
Huh?
ザインくん喋って。
Zaon-kun, speak.
ほらほら。
Look, look.
ほら、お！
Look, oh!
あれ、あれ、あれ、ちょっ、ちょっ、待って、えっ、なんでそっち行っちゃうの？
Wait, wait, wait, hold on, eh, why are you going over there?
うまい操作できねえよ、ザインが。
I can't control them well, Zaon.
俺座長なのに！
I'm the troupe leader!
ちょ、あ、こ、こ、こ、こ...
H-hold on, ah, h-, h-, h-, h-...
えっ、えっ、わかんないよ！ザインのこと全然わかんない！
Huh, huh, I don't get it! I don't understand Zaon at all!
おっ、おっ、おっ、デカイ！デカイ！デカイ！デカイ！
Oh, oh, oh, huge! Huge! Huge! Huge!
説明不要すごい！これはでかすぎる！なんで？
No explanation needed, amazing! This is way too big! Why?
いやいや、待って待って、飲み込まれるこのままじゃ。やばい。
No, no, wait wait, I'm gonna get swallowed up like this. Oh no.
あの、ポルカも披露目なんです、今日。
Um, Polka's debut is today too.
はい、ポルカはどこにいるでしょうかー？
Yes, where is Polka?
ゲーム！
Game!
3！
3!
2！
2!
1！
1!
ポルカはここですー！
Polka is right here!
イエーイ！分かったかな？
Yay! Did you figure it out?
お前らこんな巨大化もできるんだな。
You guys can get this huge too.
初めて知った。
First time knowing that.
え、ちょっとさ、これ
Um, wait a second, this
ザインくんちょっと
Zaon-kun, just
えい！あ、もっと大きくなっちゃう！
Ei! Ah, getting even bigger!
やばいやばい！ちょっと待って！
Oh no oh no! Hold on!
あ、ここすごい、ちょっとぎゃー！
Ah, this is amazing, wait, kyaa!
なに！？ちょっと！
What!? Wait!
ここ、ポルカここ！ここ！ううー、いてっ、いてっ、あそこ、ここ...
Here, Polka here! Here! Ugh, ouch, ouch, over there, here...
ザインくんにスポットライト、あの、え？
Zaon-kun, the spotlight, um, eh?
黄色、こっちか？どっちだ？
Yellow, this way? Which one?
ちょ、あの、あった、いてやっ、あ、ここ、ここ、ここ、ここ、ここ...
Hold on, um, found it, ouch, ah, here, here, here, here, here...
いや、こちらわね、あの、みんなの魔法の力でザイン増えてるから！
Well, here, um, Zaon is multiplying thanks to everyone's magic power!
あ、ちょっ、まだ動いてるよ、めちゃくちゃ動いてるよ！まだ動いてるよ！
Ah, wait, they're still moving, moving like crazy! Still moving!
あっ、入ってないよ！
Ah, I'm not inside!
ああー！なんで！？
Aah! Why!?
まだ行ける、まだいける！
Still can go, still can go!
ふっ、きょん、え？
Phew, kyon, eh?
あ、だんだんちっちゃく、あ、もうそろそろ
Ah, getting smaller and smaller, ah, pretty soon
時間だよ、座長って教えてくれてるんだ。
It's time, the troupe leader is telling me.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
やっぱ
I knew it,
在宅すげえ助かるな。
working from home is so helpful,
もう時間だよって。
telling me it's already time.
さて！
Now then!
パンっ
bam!
さあ
now,
ここまでやっておいて、
having gotten this far,
ええと…何もないのは…
um... having nothing...
なんか、言い方が分かんなくなっちゃったんだって！
I mean, I forgot how to say it!
ええと、ぜひポルカサーカスのお土産に1つこちらはいかがでしょうか？
Um, would you consider this as a souvenir from the Polka Circus?
あ
Ah,
はい！本日ポルカサーカスでお土産も販売しております！
Yes! Today we are also selling souvenirs at the Polka Circus!
というわけで、ええ、こちら！
So, um, here!
ばーん！お待たせした！3D化記念グッズ発売！
Ta-da! Sorry to keep you waiting! 3D commemorative goods on sale!
はい、ばむばむ、きたきたきた。
Yay, bam-bam, here we go!
これでアクリルスタンドと、「尻尾ラバーストラップ」＆「おまる座公演チケット風パスケース」
This includes the acrylic stand, tail rubber strap, and Omaru-za performance ticket-style pass case.
これ、すごいぜ。
This is amazing.
もう見れば…見れば分かるけどさ、すごいぜ。
If you look... if you look you'll see, it's amazing.
もう…ええと、ページが開かれたのかな？
Already... um, I wonder if the page has been opened?
できてるといいな？
Is it ready?
なんかって…ページのオープンはしてるけど、販売自体は21時からでーす！よろしくお願いします！
I mean... the page is open, but sales themselves start at 9 PM! Please check it out!
なので見ましょう。あ、待て待て、水飲むわ。
So let's take a look. Ah, wait, wait, I'm gonna drink some water.
水飲み忘れるところだったわ。
I almost forgot to drink water.
あの…1回閉めて！
Um... close it for a second!
あぶねえ、舞台裏が見えるとこだったぜ。
That was close, you almost saw behind the stage.
はい、というわけでね、お待たせしました！
Yes, so, sorry to keep you waiting!
はい、というわけで、ええ、こちらが実際3Dアクリルスタンドやってまーす！
Yes, so, um, here is the actual 3D acrylic stand!
え…どうやって写真撮ったっケ？
Um... how did I take the photo?
こうやってたの？写真撮って
Was I doing it like this? Taking a photo
せーの…せーに、なってんな。こっちは多分こうで、
One, two... it's becoming... This one is probably like this,
こうして、こう！
doing this, like this!
ええ、近くない？これ。あ、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？なかなかいい感じの…
Hey, isn't this close? Ah, isn't this good? Isn't it good? Pretty good vibe...
近いポーズになりました。
It became a close pose.
どうでしょう、どうやら。でもこっちは帽子が取れて、帽子をばーって見せてるかな？
How is it, apparently. But this one has the hat off, showing the hat off with a ta-da?
なかなかいいんじゃない？
Isn't it pretty good?
これ、大きさ何センチ？
This, what size in cm?
うーん…まあ、大きい。そこそこデカイ。
Hmm... well, it's big. Decently huge.
ええと、140ミリです。
Um, it's 140 mm.
140ミリは14センチです。
140 mm is 14 cm.
分かるかな？
Do you get it?
オッケー？じゃあ14センチのアクリルスタンドと、こちら！
Okay? Then the 14 cm acrylic stand and, here!
はい、これ見て！見てこれ！見て、ちょっと、ちょっと！これ見て！
Yes, look at this! Look at this! Look, hey, hey! Look at this!
やばくない？
Isn't it amazing?
かわいい…かわいい！
So cute... so cute!
これにはプロデューサーも納得。
Even the producer is satisfied with this.
え、あ、はい、ええと、尻尾ラバーストラップ＆のおまる座公演チケット風パスケースです！
Um, oh, yes, um, the tail rubber strap & Omaru-za performance ticket-style pass case!
よくできましたー！
Good job!
これね、分かるかな？オマルポルカって書いてある下にちゃんとポルカ、オルカって書いてある。
You know this, do you get it? Below where it says 'Omaru Polka', it properly says 'Polka', 'Oruka'.
で、ページはできてっから販売開始は9時から！
And the page is ready, so sales start at 9!
いいね。なかなか…いいんじゃない？これは普通のあれでしょ？サイズは普通のなんか
Nice. Pretty... isn't it good? This is the usual thing, right? The size is the usual kind of
あの、定形が、入る、えっと、100×70
um, standard size fits, um, 100 by 70
多分なんか普通の名刺じゃなくて、定期券入るやつ。
Probably not a regular business card, the kind that holds a commuter pass.
で、ラバーストラップこちらが40mm×80mm。
And the rubber strap here is 40mm × 80mm.
なんかね、ポルカもみたけど、これぐらい。
And you know, I saw Polka too, about this much.
あの、これ個人の感想です。
Um, this is personal opinion.
こんな感じ。これぐらい。
Like this. About this much.
一緒に付けちゃえば可愛い
if you attach them together, it's cute
ないじゃない？
Isn't that right?
あ、待って、これさ、セット販売とさ、単品販売あるよね、たしか。
Ah wait, this has a set sale and a separate sale, right?
全部グッズセット、全部セットと単品販売があるから好きな方...
There's an all-goods set, an all-set, and individual sales, so whichever you like...
全部セットが4000円で、それぞれ買うと2000円です。
The all-set is 4,000 yen, and buying them individually is 2,000 yen.
一緒に付けるのありじゃん。可愛いじゃん。
It's good to wear them together. Cute, right?
いや、あれだよほら、防振のとことかさ、尻尾のとこバラバラになってっからこれ。
No, look, the vibration-proofing part and tail part are separate here.
くっついてないよ、これちゃんとバラバラになってっから。
They aren't attached, they're properly separated.
見えるっしょ？可愛いっしょ？
You can see it, right? Cute, right?
パスケースはね、これね裏地もレーコってるから。あ、裏地のエラー出てないんだこれ。裏地もね色がねちゃんとついとるんよ。
The pass case has a lined interior too. Ah, the interior error isn't showing here. The interior lining is properly colored.
買って、見て、写真とかね。
Buy it, look at photos and stuff.
あ、今概要欄にたぶんURLがザインパワーで貼られてると思うんで、終わったら買っちゃってください。
Ah, right now, the URL is probably posted in the description by Zain Power, so please buy it when it's over.
そしてTwitterで報告しよう。いぇーい！
And let's report it on Twitter. Yay!
あ、もう一回。あ、だ。つぶやいとこ。
Ah, one more time. Ah, let me tweet.
#尾丸ポルカ3D いぇーい！
#OmaruPolka3D Yay!
いなくなった。どうしよう。
She disappeared. What should I do?
ポルカどうしたことがすっかり忘れちまってたぜ！
I completely forgot what Polka was doing!
まあいろいろやってきたけどさ、
Well, I've done various things, but...
今日は最後についにこの歌が歌えればホロライブだとポルカと思っておりました。
today finally, if I could sing this song, I thought I was hololive.
歌わせて下さい。
Please let me sing it.
いきなり行くよ！
Here we go!
Shiny Smily Story
[Title: Shiny Smily Story]
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go !
Running with our respective unique hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting in a pitch-black place wherever I looked
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were stolen by a mere tiny hope
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart swaying with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was gathering up a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting words of giving up and moving forward
苦しいときも もう私はひとりじゃないから
Even in painful times, I'm no longer alone
だからもっと夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
So I want to chase my dreams even more, the excitement won't stop
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go !
Running with our respective unique hearts, go!
仮空の空に輝く眩しい想いは 見たことのない光を現実に届けるよ
The dazzling thoughts shining in the virtual sky bring unseen light into reality
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして また新しい光を探したくなるよ
Capturing the cheers I always hear here, making me want to search for new light
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile and moving forward
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back at it in sad times gives me strength
胸を張って夢追いかけたい 奇跡の物語
Wanting to chase dreams proudly, a miracle story
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together
誰一人欠かせない 愛が舞ったこの世界
This world where love dances, where no one can be missing
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Coloring with our respective unique hearts
悲しいときも寂しいときもあるけど
Though there are sad and lonely times
信じ合えるものがある
There is something we can believe in together
忘れないでこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
Wanting to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔達
Smiles overflowing into an endless world
憧れの舞台立ちたい
Wanting to stand on the stage of admiration
らしく輝きたい
Wanting to shine in our own way
時には涙してまた笑い合いたい
Wanting to shed tears at times and laugh together again
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous step forward
ああ もう一度 気持ちが溢れ出すよ
Ah, once again, feelings are overflowing.
形あるものが 色褪せる前に この鼓動を鳴らし続けたい
Before things of form fade away, I want to keep making this heartbeat echo.
終わらない世界に飛び出そう
Let's leap into a never-ending world.
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ
Overflowing into a never-ending world—
笑顔出し
bringing out smiles!
憧れの舞台たちと らしく輝きたい
Standing on the stage of our dreams, wanting to shine in our own way.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Shedding tears at times, and wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
Wanting to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
wanting to make that dream ours.
奇跡の一歩を
Taking a miraculous step forward—
話は止まらない
The stories won't stop,
どこまでも越えていく 世界に見せてあげる
going beyond anywhere, showing it to the world.
アクセスしてみない？
Won't you try accessing it?
それぞれ誓った 踊って作るわ
Dancing and creating what each of us swore to do.
ありがとう おまるポルカでした！
Thank you, this was Omaru Polka!
ポルカ午後におるよ！
Polka will be here in the afternoon too!
ポルカからもよろしくね！
Please keep supporting Polka!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!